All right, let's do some more fun stuff.
我们再进行一些有趣的设置
So what I want to do in this video is I want to add some animations to the specific text.
在本视频中 我将对这些文本添加一些动画效果
So whenever this text or whichever direction we are heading changes,
每当这个文本 也就是方向改变时
I want to go ahead and animate that change and kind of bounce the text a little bit.
我希望这种改变能有个动画效果 使文本能跳转下
So what we'll do is we're going to use react-native's animated library.
我们将使用 react-native 的 Animated 库
The very first thing we're going to do is add
首先 向状态中
a bounce value to our state which is going to be
添加一个 bounceValue
a new instance of calling animated.value with a capital v and passing in once.
将为调用 Animated.Value 的新实例 V 大写 并传入 1
The bounceValue is going to start at one.
bounceValue 将从 1 开始
And then what we're going to do is down here.
然后转到下面
Let's see inside of set location.
进入 setLocation 中
The reason we set it up like this is because what I want to do here is,
这么设置的原因是
and this is where we're going to determine if the specific direction we're heading has
我们想在这里判断我们的朝向是否改变了
changed because we have the old direction and then we also have the new direction.
这是旧方向 这是新方向
So what we can say, is we can say if new direction does not equal the old direction,
如果 newDirection 不等于旧的 direction
then what we want to do is we want to
则我们希望对 bounceValue
take our bounceValue and we want to animate it a little bit.
设置一个动画效果
So what we can do is we can say Animated.sequence
输入 Animated.sequence
meaning we're going to have a sequence of animations.
表示我们将实现一系列的动画效果
We're going to pass in an array.
传入一个数组
The very first animation we're going to do is it's going to be timed,
第一个动画将计时
so using Animated.timing what we
因此使用 Animated.timing
want to animate or what we want to change is the bounceValue.
我们想更改的是 bounceValue
And then we want this to take 200 milliseconds,
持续时间为 200 毫秒
and we want to go from an initial value that we set at 1 to 1.04.
我们想从初始值 1 变成 1.04
So that sounds small but you'll see it in action here in a second.
听起来很小 但是很快就会看到实际效果的
And then once that's complete what we want to do is we want
上述动画完成后
to do a spring animation on our bounceValue again.
我们希望对 bounceValue 再次设置跳转动画效果
And now what we want to do is go back to a value of one with a friction of four.
现在我们希望回到值 1 friction 为 4
So what's going to happen here,
发生的过程是
our bounceValue is going to start at one.
bounceValue 从 1 开始
When the location changes,
当位置改变时
we're going to take it from one, time it,
从 1 开始
taking 200 milliseconds up to 1.04,
计时 200 毫秒后 变成 1.04
and then take it back down to one using a spring.
然后使用 spring 属性回到 1
And what you always need to remember is that
务必要记住的是
with animations you need to call.start on them.
对于动画 始终需要调用 .start
So now what's going to happen right now is bounceValue
现在看看应用效果…
is undefined that's because we need to come in here and say bounceValue.
bounceValue 未定义 因为我们需要在这里输入 bounceValue
So we shouldn't see anything just yet because we haven't
暂时不会看到任何动画效果
actually tied up this bounceValue to our UI.
因为我们尚未将此 bounceValue 关联到我们的 UI
So what we can do is down here inside
转到下面的
of our end of component where we're going to use this instead,
render 组件中 我们将...
where is that? Right here.
跑哪去了？在这
Instead of having just text components what we can say
我们将这里的 Text
is we want these to be Animated.Text components,
改为 Animated.Text
we just want to bring this down.
将这个挪到下一行
And then now what we want to do is we want it to
现在 我们要做的是...
have the style that it had which was styles that direction,
它本来具有 styles.direction
but we also want to give it a transform.
我们还希望添加 transform
So the way that will look is something like this, we'll say transform,
看起来是这样的 我们将输入 transform:
we'll pass it an array and we want it to scale with our bounceValue.
传入一个数组 对 bounceValue 进行缩放
So now as the bounceValue is changing that's going to
现在 当 bounceValue 改变时
scale and transform this specific text.
将缩放和转换这一文本
So that looks pretty good to me,
看起来不错
I think that is it.
差不多设置完毕了
We need real quick up here to grab bounceValue off of this state.
需要快速转到这里 从 this.state 上获取 bounceValue
All right, it looks good. Let's go ahead and test this out.
看起来不错 我们测试下代码
So I'm going to go here.
转到这个界面
So you'll notice right away it changed from west to northwest and we got that animation.
立即从 West 变成了 North West 并出现了一个动画效果
Let's wait a few more seconds,
再等几秒
hopefully we'll get another direction change here as
希望能再次改变方向
we're on the freeway going 75 miles per hour.
因为我们在高速公路上以 75 英里/小时的速度前进
There we go. We went back to west and you'll notice
方向改变了 变成了 West
we got the subtle little animation change there.
你会发现比较细微的动画变化效果